let's look at the solution to a rate
zero quiz where we have an array of four
disks
and for one disk we know the capacity
throughput and mttf
in raid 0 we're striping the data across
all the disks with no redundancy so we
can use the capacity of all four disks
and thus get
800 gigabytes in capacity
if we spread the read and write load
evenly across the disks then one disk
being able to support 10 megabytes per
second and four disks being used in
parallel like this
gives us a throughput of 40 megabytes
per second and finally
if the mttf for one disk is a hundred
thousand hours
the expected mttf for the whole array is
going to be a quarter of this if they
are in raid 0
so we will get 25
000 hours
this mttf ends up being almost 12 years
this one is almost three years
if we plan to replace our array after
something like five or six years
know that it can still fail within the
five to six years
but on average it's going to last
about 12 years however here our average
array is going to fail during the five
to six years
so obviously with such a low mttf we
should not have used four disks in raid
0 like this